Lowell Thomas Papers: Objects
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Lowell Thomas Papers: Objects
1789 - 1984
1900 - 1981
npkmc-225-122
1203 Linear Feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Thomas, Lowell, 1892-1981
The Lowell Thomas Papers encompasses a wide range of materials documenting the life, family, and professional career of Lowell Thomas. These materials include correspondence, administrative and financial documents, manuscripts, printed materials, photographic materials, motion picture films, audio recordings, and memorabilia.
Collection Overview
This series consists of a wide range of memorabilia and realia, including portraits, photographic equipment, furniture, clothing, hats, and other items belonging to Lowell Thomas, Lowell Thomas, Jr., or Harry G. Thomas. Of particular interest is the collection of printing plates used to produce, among other materials, promotional posters for Thomas's travelogues. The series is divided into eight subseries, some divided further into sub subseries, all arranged by subject. A project to create digital images of these objects is on-going.
The Lowell Thomas Papers were donated to Marist College by the Thomas family in 2006.
Historical Note
Lowell Jackson Thomas was born in Woodington, Ohio on 6 April 1892 to two school teachers, Harry G. Thomas and Harriet Wagner Thomas. The family did not remain in Darke County, Ohio for very long because Lowell's father wanted to become a doctor. Harry G. Thomas's pursuit of a medical degree led the family to Kirkman, Iowa where five-year-old Lowell was enrolled in school for the first time. Harry's studies soon led him to the University of Nebraska. Upon graduation, Harry G. Thomas followed his brother's suggestion to begin his medical practice in the twin mining boom towns of Cripple Creek and Victor, Colorado. It was here in the rugged American West that Lowell spent the better part of his childhood and young adult years.
Read more
There are no restrictions on this collection
Related Collections
Lowell Thomas Film Collection
Lowell Thomas Memorabilia Collection
Lowell Thomas Papers: Graphic Materials
Lowell Thomas Papers: Sound Recordings
Lowell Thomas Papers: Textual Materials
Arrangement of the Collection
These records are organized into 8 series: 1) Family, with three subseries, 2) Clubs, 3) Equipment, 4) Sports, 5) Tibet, 6) World War I/Travelogues, 7) World War II, 8) Miscellany, with two subseries. Subseries 8.2 has seven subseries.
The Marist College Archives and Special Collections staff wishes to express their deep appreciation to all of the parties that helped the Lowell Thomas Project come to fruition.
Read more
- 1. Family, 1; Boxes: 1647 - 1667
  Series contains objects from Lowell Thomas, Lowell Thomas Jr., and Harry G. Thomas.
  By person
  - Subseries 1.1: Lowell Thomas, 1.1; Boxes: 1647 - 1664
    - Lowell Thomas’s “Open Road” style Stetson fedora hat in Silver Belly 3x fur felt. Sold by Norman Sims “Hatter”, Salt Lake City, Utah. Size, 7¼ inches. Lowell Thomas’s initials stamped in gold on the sweatband, undated (Folder 1, Box 1647)
    - Lowell Thomas’s red wine colored wool felt Egyptian fez hat. Circular/round hat with flat top and black thread tassel with straw interior. Interior dark green in color. Stamped on sweatband is a nighttime desert landscape with two pyramids, palm trees and obelisk, circa 1940s (Folder 1, Box 1648)
    - Lowell Thomas’s sun helmet (safari or desert sun hat). Very fine cotton twill hat of sturdy construction with asymmetrical, angled brim, flat crown that has a cross-the-hat top leather band and buckle, and pleated fabric band. Deep pink cotton interior with crossed web for air flow. Medium size, undated (Folder 1, Box 1649)
    - LC Smith Corona typewriter, undated (Folder 1, Box 1650)
    - Two glass bottles from Cripple Creek & Victor Company, one bearing “The Pioneer Bottling Works. Victor, Co.” trademark and the other “The Standard Bottling Mfg. Co. Cripple Creek Colo.” [items are located in Lowell Thomas Gallery], circa early 1900s (Folder 1-2, Box 1651)
    - One VIEW-MASTER viewing device, circa 1960s (Folder 1, Box 1652)
    - Gramophone speaker with black cast iron base, black neck and wood end. Manufacturer logo inside horn reads “Music Master, Reproducer, Philadelphia, PA, USA”, circa 1920s (Folder 1, Box 1653)
    - Stewart Warner radio made in Chicago, Illinois by the Stewart Warner Speed Corporation. Metal sides and hinged wooden top; contains five vacuum tubes. Measures approximately 8¼ x 9 x 20 ½ inches., undated (Folder 1, Box 1654)
    - Portrait of Lowell Thomas by Joseph A. Maturo (signed Jos. A. Maturo). Measures 38 x 29 inches., circa 1930s (Folder 1, Box 1655)
    - 1968 desk calendar (used) torn off to Monday May, 13. Still in plastic faux wood finish calendar holder (Folder 1, Box 1656)
    - Empty plastic faux wood finish desk calendar holder, undated (Folder 2, Box 1656)
    - Empty brown metal desk calendar holder, undated (Folder 3, Box 1656)
    - Empty black art deco desk calendar holder, undated (Folder 4, Box 1656)
    - Worn bound desk note pad and pencil (used), inscribed with the name “Lowell Thomas” in gold lettering on the cover, undated (Folder 5, Box 1656)
    - Large block of Lucite containing a large steel nut and note card. Note reads “Mr. Lowell Thomas: This is a nut off the right hand side recoil mechanism of one of Count Felix von Luckner’s guns. Removed from the wreck of the SEEADLER on the reef at the isle of Mopelia, French Oceania, on April 25th, 1956 by Ralph Varady, Sincerely, Ralph Varady, Honolulu, Sept. 26th 1958”. Measures 6 x 6 x 2 inches (Folder 6, Box 1656)
    - Dark brown/black bifold wallet bearing the name “Lowell Thomas” in gold lettering. Wallet contains two business cards of differing sizes 2 x 3 and 1½ x 3 inches respectively. Typeface on cards reads “Mr. Lowell Thomas”, undated (Folder 7, Box 1656)
    - 1965 desk calendar (used) torn off to Tuesday, January 5. Contained in distinctive green leather desk calendar holder with 24k gold inlay reading “Lowell Thomas” on cover flap. Small gold tag on bottom reads “A&M Leatherlines Inc., New York, N.Y., Genuine Leather, 24k tooled” (Folder 8, Box 1656)
    - Desktop pen holder and clock in distinctive green and gold leather motif with gold typeface reading “Lowell Thomas” centered in front of the clock. Small gold tag on bottom reads “A&M Leatherlines Inc., New York, N.Y., Genuine Leather, 24k tooled” Measures 10 x 4½ inches, 1965 (Folder 9, Box 1656)
    - Small desktop lighter in distinctive green and gold leather motif. Small gold tag on bottom reads “A&M Leatherlines Inc., New York, N.Y., Genuine Leather, 24k tooled” Measures 2 x 3½ inches, 1965 (Folder 10, Box 1656)
    - Desktop ashtray in distinctive green and gold leather motif. Small gold tag on bottom reads “A&M Leatherlines Inc., New York, N.Y., Genuine Leather, 24k tooled” Measures 1½ x 8½ inches, 1965 (Folder 11, Box 1656)
    - A large metallic letter “T” measuring 9½ x 6½ inches, 1965 (Folder 12, Box 1656)
    - CBS NEWS lapel pin measuring 1½ x 2 inches, undated (Folder 13, Box 1656)
    - Lowell Thomas’s Distinguished Service Award, presented to him by the National Association of Broadcasting, Chicago, Illinois, April, 1968. Measures 11½ x 15 inches (Folder 1, Box 1657)
    - Lowell Thomas’s 1981 Audio - Visual Media Educator Recognition Award, presented to him August 5, 1981 by the National Audio Visual Association. Measures 10 x 15 inches (Folder 2, Box 1657)
    - Small red change purse containing eight assorted keys, undated (Folder 3, Box 1657)
    - Unidentified brass object measuring 4 x 1½ inches, undated (Folder 4, Box 1657)
    - Small circular tape measure, measuring 2 x ¼ inches, undated (Folder 5, Box 1657)
    - Small fold-out magnifying glass, undated (Folder 6, Box 1657)
    - Two small replacement vacuum tubes for a tape recorder, wrapped in paper, undated (Folder 7, Box 1657)
    - Small empty plastic container once containing “Tape Recorder Head Cleaning Fluid.” Measures 3½ x 2 inches, undated (Folder 8, Box 1657)
    - Reel to reel rewind setup produced by the Craig Movie Supply Company. In original box. Measures approximately 6 x 4½ x 3½ inches, undated (Folder 9, Box 1657)
    - Four Philadelphia Evening Bulletin delegate signs, undated (Folder 10, Box 1657)
    - Circular photo frame. Measures 6½ x 6½ inches, late 1800s - early 1900s (Folder 11, Box 1657)
    - Lowell Thomas Inn dinnerware cup, black and yellow motif, undated (Folder 1, Box 1658)
    - Lowell Thomas Inn dinnerware saucer, black and yellow motif, undated (Folder 2, Box 1658)
    - Lowell Thomas Inn dinnerware bowl, black and yellow motif, undated (Folder 3, Box 1658)
    - Lowell Thomas Inn dinnerware dish, black and yellow motif, undated (Folder 4, Box 1658)
    - Lowell Thomas Inn dinnerware dinner dish, black and yellow motif, undated (Folder 5, Box 1658)
    - Large, worn, brown steamer trunk with the word “Beirut” hand painted on side. Trunk is empty and measures 31 x 17 x 13 inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1659)
    - Recognition plaque given to Lowell Thomas on 6 May 1981 by the University of South Carolina to honor the establishment of a scholarship in broadcast journalism, 1981 May 6 (Folder 1, Box 1660)
    - Lowell Thomas Board Game from Parker Brothers, 1937 (Folder 1, Box 1661)
    - Gold framed embroidery textiles [Indian?][Tibetan?]. Measure 30 ½ x 28½ inches [items are located in Marist College Special Collections hanging storage area], undated (Folder 1, Box 1662)
    - Reddish-orange silk scarf with an intricate design [Indian?][Tibetan?], undated (Folder 1, Box 1663)
    - Decorative sash, purple with a pattern of shapes that are blue, gold, pink and orange in color. There is also an intricate design of colorful beads on one side [Indian?][Tibetan?], undated (Folder 2, Box 1663)
    - Decorative bag with a complex design. The primary colors are red, burgundy, green, pink, yellow and blue. Tassels are affixed to the bag [Indian or Tibetan?], undated (Folder 3, Box 1663)
    - Decorative bag, mainly burgundy in color. There is a design of shells and two tassels affixed to bag [Indian?][Tibetan?], undated (Folder 4, Box 1663)
    - Decorative bag with a pattern in colors of green, burgundy, pink, and yellow [Indian?][Tibetan?], undated (Folder 5, Box 1663)
    - Lowell Thomas’s Honorary Doctorate from Marist College with President Dennis J. Murray’s signature. Latin language. Measures 18 x 22 inches (including frame), 1981 May 16 (Folder 1, Box 1664)
  - Subseries 1.2: Lowell Thomas, Jr., 1.2; Boxes: 1665 - 1666
    - Brown, long sleeve, button down military shirt with Air Force patch insignia on left sleeve. Collar label reads “Custom Tailored by Schwartz, Cincinnati, Dry Clean Only”, circa 1940S (Folder 1, Box 1665)
    - Pair of khaki colored men’s shorts, Abercrombie & Fitch, undated (Folder 2, Box 1665)
    - Large tan raincoat lining, undated (Folder 3, Box 1665)
    - Khaki colored long sleeve button down shirt size 15½ - 35. Collar label reads “Saks & Co. 611 5th Ave., N.Y.”, undated (Folder 4, Box 1665)
    - Pair of khaki colored men’s shorts, undated (Folder 5, Box 1665)
    - Brown heavyweight riding pants with tan leather patches at the inside knee, undated (Folder 6, Box 1665)
    - Tan heavyweight riding pants with light tan leather patches at the inside knee, undated (Folder 7, Box 1665)
    - Large brown raincoat lining, undated (Folder 1, Box 1666)
    - Dark tan heavyweight riding pants with leather patches at the inside knee, undated (Folder 2, Box 1666)
    - Light tan heavyweight riding pants with leather patches at the inside knee, undated (Folder 3, Box 1666)
    - Light tan riding pants with lace up leg bottoms, undated (Folder 4, Box 1666)
    - Worn, dark brown leather briefcase, with a brass clasp and initials “L.T. jr.” on front, undated (Folder 5, Box 1666)
    - Copper potato chip award given to Lowell Thomas Jr. in 1954. Inscribed “Chip off the old block, From the National Potato Chip Institute, to Lowell Thomas Jr., 1954”. Includes marble stand. Measures approximately 4¾ x 4½ inches (Folder 6, Box 1666)
  - Subseries 1.3: Harry G. Thomas, 1.3; Box: 1667
    - Wooden box containing stainless steel physician’s tools. Measuring approximately 12 x 6 x 2 inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1667)
- 2. Clubs, 2; Boxes: 1668 - 1669
  Series contains objects from The Explorers Club
  By Club
  - Subseries 2.1: The Explorers Club, 2.1; Boxes: 1668 - 1669
    - Bronze bust of Lowell Thomas, measuring 9 x 14¼ inches. American Sculptor Philip Kraczkowski was commissioned by The Explorers Club to sculpt the bust, circa 1969 (Folder 1, Box 1668)
    - The Explorers Club 75th Anniversary Award. Bronze medallion encased in Lucite reading “Lowell Thomas Award, The Explorers Club 1905, Lowell Thomas”, 1980 October 17 (Folder 1, Box 1669)
- 3. Equipment, 3; Boxes: 1670 - 1697
  - Cine Kodak 16mm [millimeter] movie camera, manufactured by Eastman Kodak (Rochester, New York) from 1925-1931. Leather covered metal camera body. Measures 5 x 9 inches, circa 1925 - 1935 (Folder 1, Box 1670)
  - DeVry Motion Picture Camera 7 x 9 inches manufactured by DeVry Corporation (Chicago, Illinois). Equipped with Kodak Anastigmat lens, circa 1930s (Folder 1, Box 1671)
  - Camerette 16, 35 [51 x 39 inches] standard reflex movie camera with lens. Manufactured in Éclair, Paris. With Éclair Tripod, undated (Folder 1, Box 1672)
  - Kodascope radio rewind universal splicer, measuring approximately 6½ x 29½ x 5½ inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1673)
  - BUHL 8 (inch), 3.9 lens for carousel/ektagraphic slide projector, boxed, undated (Folder 1, Box 1674)
  - Black hard shell lantern slide carrying case. With silver clasp and key. Measures approximately 10½ x 8½ x 5½ inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1675)
  - Leather camera case. Enclosed in the case is Kodak film. Measures 10¼ x 8 x 8 1/2 inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1676)
  - Cine Kodak Model B movie camera case. Manufactured by the Eastman Kodak Company. Measures 10½ x 4½ x 7½ inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1677)
  - Camera box which contains a Kinoptik lens. Box measures approximately 12 x 5 x 9¼ inches, undated (Folder 2, Box 1677)
  - RCA Radiola with the head set. Measures 8½ x 6½ x 5 inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1678)
  - Motion picture camera equipment (6 pieces). Includes 2 Kinoptik lenses (Paris F 2S Focale, 150 mm, No. 24818, Kinoptik Paris, Odyssey), undated (Folder 1, Box 1679)
  - Trans Twinister/Gates M1568 model. Measures 7½ x 6¼ inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1680)
  - G. Nicks audio head set, undated (Folder 2, Box 1680)
  - Philco radio (wooden case). Model 37-60, Palt. 10226-A. Measures 20 x 16 x 10 inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1681)
  - Bronze presentation plaque. Part of the radio “Star of Stars Contest” by readers of Radio Guide, 1936. Most popular news commentator. Measures 6 x 9 inches (Folder 1, Box 1682)
  - Graflex Camera (folding box camera). Measures 6 x 6 x 7 inches, undated (Folder 2, Box 1682)
  - 2 “Woodsman’s Pals” (machetes), undated (Folder 1, Box 1683)
  - Estwing Chisel Point Rock Hammer. Measures about 12 inches, undated (Folder 2, Box 1683)
  - Gray Audiograph equipment. Measures 8½ x 9½ x 5 inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1684)
  - Realist 620 slide projector. Measures 12 x 7½ x 4½ inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1685)
  - Bell & Howell Film Sound Projector. Measures 9 x 20 x 9 inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1686)
  - 2 wooden book blocks. Measure 7 x 6 x 2¼ inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1687)
  - Needles from Speak O-Phone personal phonograph records, undated (Folder 1, Box 1688)
  - Equipment possibly related to the development of film. A wooden box contains a mirror as well as a light. Measures 13¼ x10½ x 3 inches, undated (Folder 2, Box 1688)
  - Black library card catalog cabinet with two drawers. Measures 12 x 12 x 4½ inches, circa 1930s (Folder 1- 2, Box 1689)
  - Black library card catalog cabinet with two drawers. Measures 12 x 12 x 4½ inches, circa 1930s (Folder 1, Box 1690)
  - Wooden black lantern slide holder. The holder is open and contains two tan straps at either end. Measures 12½ x 4 x 4 inches, undated (Folder 2 - 3, Box 1690)
  - A green, metal film index card cabinet. Measures 16 x 6½ 5 inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1691)
  - Kodachrome 35 millimeter slide box. Holds up to 100 slides. Measures 6 x 10 x 2½ inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1692)
  - Kodak 35 millimeter slide carousel. Holds up to 140 slides. Measures approximately 10 x 10 x 2½ inches, circa 1970s (Folder 2, Box 1692)
  - Kodak 35 millimeter slide carousel. It can hold up to 140 slides. Measures approximately 10 x 10 x 2½ inches, circa 1970s (Folder 3, Box 1692)
  - Kodak 35 millimeter slide carousel. It can hold up to 80 slides. Measures approximately 10 x 10 x 2½ inches, circa 1970s (Folder 4, Box 1692)
  - One of several handmade wooden crates that housed Frank R. Roberson’s glass plate negatives. Measures 16 x 11 x 10 inches, circa early 1900s (Folder 1, Box 1693)
  - Wooden crate used to house glass plate negatives. Measures 13¼ x 7½ x 8 inches, circa 1920s (Folder 1, Box 1694)
  - Brown, portable file cabinet used by Lowell Thomas, Jr. Measures 12½ 5½ x 12 inches, circa 1940s (Folder 1, Box 1695)
  - Brown phonograph record album box. Measures 12 x 4½ x 13 inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1696)
  - Brown phonograph record album box. Measures 13 x 6½ x 13 inches, undated (Folder 2, Box 1697)
  - Memorex Mark III computer memory disk. United States patent number 3,474,073. Measures 1½ x 15 inches, circa 1970s (Folder 1, Box 1697)
- 4. Sports, 4; Box: 1698
  - Vintage practice hockey puck, unused and still in original box. Label on box reads “Alex Taylor Co. Inc., The House that Sport Built, 22 East 42nd St. New York, N.Y., No.P., Practice Puck”. Puck itself is stamped with company logo and address, undated (Folder 1 - 2, Box 1698)
  - Vintage Spalding Duro Seam Softball, unused and in original box and wrapping, undated (Folder 3 - 4, Box 1698)
- 5. Tibet, 5; Boxes: 1699 - 1712
  - Handmade wool Tibetan hat with distinctive pointed ear flaps and asymmetrical design using colorful striped wool in gold, blue, silver and black and hand-embroidered flowers. Vibrant red interior, circa 1940s (Folder 1, Box 1699)
  - Tibetan copper urn with holder and top. Decoratively tooled exterior featuring brass appliqué. Measures 13½ x 16½ inches, circa 1940s (Folder 1, Box 1700)
  - Tibetan Long Horn, three-piece, telescoping extension stored in the closed position. Decorative metal clasp attached to wide end of horn with additional decorative metal work at the end of each extension and mouthpiece. The Rag-Dung is a ceremonial instrument that is played to accompany chanting., circa 1940s (Folder 1, Box 1701)
  - A pair of well-worn wooden crutches used by Lowell Thomas after he broke his hip from a horseback fall on leaving Tibet, 1949 (Folder 1, Box 1702)
  - Tibetan handcrafted beaded bangle bracelet in geometric design. Glass beads of green, ochre, burgundy, dark blue and white on padded cloth, circa 1940s (Folder 1, Box 1703)
  - Loomed Tibetan cotton satchel in blue, pink and burgundy on off-white field. Pull-tie closure, containing a collection of exotic sea shells, circa 1940s (Folder 2, Box 1703)
  - A set of raw leather reins, circa 1940s (Folder 3, Box 1703)
  - Tibetan painted ceremonial mask depicting a fanged mythological creature. Measures approximately 12 x 13 x 2 inches, circa 1940s (Folder 4, Box 1703)
  - Tibetan painted ceremonial mask depicting a mythological creature. Measures approximately 7 x 7 x 2 inches, circa 1940s (Folder 5, Box 1703)
  - Carved circular wooden Tibetan bowl containing four small dice and twenty-two copper coins. Measures 4 x 1½ inches, circa 1940s (Folder 6, Box 1703)
  - Carved circular wooden Tibetan bowl containing twenty-six metallic pegs. Measures 4 x 1½ inches, circa 1940s (Folder 7, Box 1703)
  - Unidentified sewn circular leather disc measuring 7½ x 1 inches, circa 1940s (Folder 8, Box 1703)
  - Brass Tibetan candle stand, silver plated with etched and colored floral motif. Measures 7¾ x 8½ inches, circa 1940s (Folder 1, Box 1704)
  - Brass Tibetan candle stand, with etched silver and brass plating. Measures 7 x 7¼ inches, circa 1940s (Folder 2, Box 1704)
  - Conical shaped Tibetan hat made of palm leaves overlaid with fabric appliqué containing colorful felt flowers, circa 1940s (Folder 1, Box 1705)
  - Traditional Tibetan apron of striped woven material overlaid with gold, floral-patterned damask at upper corners. Woven ribbon tie. Backed with synthetic turquoise fabric in geometric pattern, circa 1940s (Folder 2, Box 1705)
  - Lowell Thomas’s personal circular/round multi-colored fabric hat with flat top. Has a woven appearance and black fabric interior. Gift of the Lamas of the Tibetan holy city of Lhasa during Lowell Thomas’s 1949 visit, circa 1949 (Folder 1, Box 1706)
  - Lowell Thomas’s personal circular hat with flat crown and brim in gold lacquer with Southeast Asian decorative motif. Crown has air holes surrounded by stylized Asian symbols. Padded cloth sweatband and red silk under chin ties, undated (Folder 2, Box 1706)
  - Lowell Thomas’s personal Tibetan appliqué hat with brim. Woven green silk head band and woven silk crown appliqué outlined in red. Navy blue string to hold hat in place. Red silk lined crown and lower brim. Golden rick rack trim at edge of brim and on hat band, circa 1940s (Folder 1, Box 1707)
  - Lowell Thomas’s personal hand sewn Tibetan style long robe in aged cream silk with mandarin collar and fuchsia pink partial lining, circa 1940s (Folder 2, Box 1707)
  - Four ecru silk napkins/hand towels with colorful hand embroidery depicting four Tibetan village scenes, two male and two female: farming crops, hunting game, weaving fabric and churning butter. Measures 17 x 9½ inches, circa 1940s (Folder 3, Box 1707)
  - Three identical, colorful, woven Tibetan textiles. Measures approximately 25 x 7 inches, circa 1940s (Folder 4, Box 1707)
  - Tibetan flag in traditional colors with rising sun motif from the late 1960s - 1970s, circa 1960s - 1970s (Folder 5, Box 1707)
  - Collection of seven Tibetan ceremonial white silk scarves with frayed edges, 1949 (Folder 1, Box 1708)
  - Collection of four Tibetan ceremonial white scarves in assorted fabrics with frayed fringe edges, 1949 (Folder 2, Box 1708)
  - Lowell Thomas’s personal Tibetan ceremonial red silk scarf. Handwritten note by Lowell Thomas accompanies scarf: “Tibetan ceremonial scarves. Red scarves are usually given by Dalai Lama”, 1949 (Folder 3, Box 1708)
  - Tibetan ceremonial red silk scarf, 1949 (Folder 4, Box 1708)
  - Collection of seventeen handcrafted handheld fans, embroidered on one or both sides in colorful floral designs. The fabrics use an assortment of patterns, fabrics and shapes, 1949 (Folder 5, Box 1708)
  - Stone carving of praying Buddha. Measures 8½ x 12 inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1709)
  - 5 copper engraving plates. 2 measure 2½ x 1½ inches; 2 measure 1¾ x 1¾ inches; 1 measures 3 x 1½ inches; All have a height of ¾ of an inch, undated (Folder 2, Box 1709)
  - Seven pieces of Tibetan silver, undated (Folder 1, Box 1710)
  - Tibetan beaded necklace with pendant. Round and oblong beads inlaid with turquoise and silver, undated (Folder 2, Box 1710)
  - Tibetan bracelet. Floret shaped beads inlaid with turquoise and silver, undated (Folder 3, Box 1710)
  - Hand sewn Tibetan Thangka. Measures 27 x 25 inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1711)
  - Tibetan flag given to Lowell Thomas by the fourteenth Dalai Lama when they met in Lhasa in 1949. The flag is both machine and hand stitched, and embroidered with colored thread. Measures 43½ x 45 inches [item stored in oversize tube], circa 1940s (Folder 1, Box 1712)
- 6. World War I/Travelogues, 1914 - 1918; 6; Boxes: 1713 - 1721